PROPHET T.B. JOSHUA VISITS THE CITY OF JERUSALEM
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits The Site Of The New ZAKA Headquarters, Jerusalem, Israel
In the heart of the ancient city of Jerusalem is situated the new headquarters of ZAKA,
the renowned and UN-recognized disaster victim identification organization in Israel.
Joined by Rabbi Yehuda Meshi Zahav, chairman and co-founder of ZAKA, Prophet T.B. Joshua visited the site
of the new ZAKA headquarters to review the design of the building.
We want to bring the design so you can see it here.
So, there will be an entrance from the road.
Here we have “Israel Care” as Prophet asked.
We also believe in it and spoke to our volunteers who think it is a very good idea
because at the end of the day, we are here to give care to everybody.
Once we go in, we have our different offices.
We have our international dispatch center.
We have our conference room.
Downstairs, we have all the equipment we need if there is a war or something big around the world.
All the different units we have in ZAKA, each of them will have a room in this building.
In here, we can continue the love the Prophet always speaks about, all around the world.
The Rabbi says the most important thing is that the Prophet’s office in Jerusalem is here.
This is your home.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits The Site Of The New ZAKA Headquarters, Jerusalem, Israel
Where is this tree here?
One of the main things ZAKA is trying to do around the world is also avoiding bad things.
We will have classes here to show people the harm that happens everywhere
and how we can change and be better people.
Once we are better people, we work from our heart.
We love each other and we help other people.
Rabbi wants to say something.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits The Site Of The New ZAKA Headquarters, Jerusalem, Israel
Rabbi says the way you see the layout outside is the real layout.
What is important here is that there is a lot of light in this building.
We believe that we can "open the light" to other people, to everybody.
It is wonderful.
We want you to keep it, Prophet.
Thank you very much.
This is your office in Jerusalem.
No problem.
Everything big starts little.
Look at this place; it starts little but it becomes big tomorrow.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits The Site Of The New ZAKA Headquarters, Jerusalem, Israel
Rabbi says this is the beginning but we are with you all the way.
Under the name "Israel Care", the new ZAKA headquarters is designed to include a permanent office
for the man of God - Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Rabbi Yehuda embraces the Prophet at the site of the new ZAKA headquarters,
showing him that he has a home in Israel.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits The Site Of The New ZAKA Headquarters, Jerusalem, Israel
Prophet T.B. Joshua Arrives For A Meeting With Religious Leaders In Jerusalem
Accompanied by Rabbi Yehuda, Prophet T.B. Joshua meets with renowned religious leaders in Jerusalem
to discuss unity and peace.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Arrives For A Meeting With Religious Leaders In Jerusalem
Welcome!
I’m Rabbi David Rosen; a great pleasure to meet you.
Thank you.
This is Mr Oded Wiener.
We have already met.
Shalom. Trond Bakkevig from Norway.
Hello; I’m Bishop Munib Younan.
Hajj Salah Zuheka.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Arrives For A Meeting With Religious Leaders In Jerusalem
I am Trond Bakkevig; I am the Convener of the Council of Religious Institutions of the Holy Land.
We created the Council of Religious Institutions in order to have a continuous entity
where we could meet constantly from all three religions and you are here.
The Council was created in order to have open lines of communication between religious leaders
so that through good times and bad times and in crisis situations,
there is a possibility of communication to solve problems,
which we have sometimes managed to do.
It is all about love; God is love.
Like the Book of 1 Corinthians 13:13 says, the greatest is love.
Also in the Hebrew Bible, the love of God appears many more times than the fear of God.
Thank you.
Let us love one another.
God is love.
We must love one another.
If we preach in love and faith, God preaches.
If we teach in love and faith, God teaches.
Love looks around to see who is in need, who is crying, who is unsafe.
That is love.
Failing to walk in love almost shuts down our spiritual walk with the Lord.
When I met Rabbi, I realised what he is doing in Jerusalem, Israel and all over the world
transcends the issue of religion.
I said we have to come together and see what we could do.
We cannot just look to the other side.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Arrives For A Meeting With Religious Leaders In Jerusalem
In his meeting with religious leaders from the Council of Religious Institutions of the Holy Land,
Prophet T.B. Joshua emphasizes on the importance of love, as the language that transcends all barriers
of race, religion, nationality and culture.
Love is the greatest.
If love is the greatest, there is nothing we can do without love.
All our efforts and attributes without love are nothing.
Thank you for coming.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Meets With Religious Leaders in Jerusalem
As Prophet T.B. Joshua says, "The world needs to see our unity and our love for one another".
In a gesture of unity, the religious leaders of the Holy Land exchange hand shakes with the Prophet
and express their desire to work together.
My name is Rabbi David Rosen.
As I mentioned earlier, once upon a time, I was Rabbi of Seapoint in Cape Town, South Africa.
I was then Chief Rabbi of Ireland.
I have been back in Israel since 1985.
I am the Advisor of the Chief Rabbinate of Israel on International Relations.
I am part of the Steering Committee of The Council Of Religious Institutions Of The Holy Land.
I am Oded Wiener.
I used to be the Director General of the Chief Rabbinate of Israel for 14 years.
Before that, for 12 years, I was in charge of all the Jewish Holy Sites in Israel.
Now, I am Advisor to the Chief Rabbinate of Israel on all Interfaith Dialogue around the world.
It is very interesting to hear about his work for the poor and needy around the world.
It’s not just in Nigeria but countries like Colombia, Haiti
and other countries where we heard about his noble work.
It is very interesting to know the person and hear about his unbelievable work.
It is an honour for us to meet such a great person.
Our job here is to promote peace and work together.
We would be honoured and glad to work together.
I am Trond Bakkevig; I am a priest of the Church of Norway, Lutheran Church.
I am here in Jerusalem because I am the Convener of The Council Of Religious Institutions Of The Holy Land.
The purpose of the Council is to bring the religious leaders of Jerusalem and the Holy Land together
which are the three religions – the Jewish, the Christians and the Muslims,
in order to make them an instrument for peace in this land.
It is nice to meet him and good to hear what he is doing.
It is impressive to hear what he is doing for relief work around the world.
I hope we can continue our contacts.
I am Bishop Munib Younan; I am the Lutheran Bishop of Jerusalem.
Council Of Religious Institutions Of The Holy Land
Bishop Munib Younan, French President Hollande
Bishop Munib Younan With Pope Francis
Prophet T.B. Joshua Meets With Religious Leaders In Jerusalem
U.S. Vice President Joe Biden With Bishop Younan, Salah Zuheyka, Trond Bakkevig, Oded Wiener
UK Prime Minister Tony Blair With Salah Zuheyka, Bishop Younan, Rabbi David Rosen, Oded Wiener
Hilary Clinton With Oded Wiener, Trond Bakkevig, Bishop Younan and Sahah Zuheyka
Prophet T.B. Joshua Meets With Religious Leaders In Jerusalem
T.B. Joshua Arrives At The Jerusalem Municipality To Meet With The Deputy Mayor Of Jerusalem
In the square, an acquaintance of the ZAKA founder Rabbi Yehuda welcomes the Prophet to Jerusalem.
Welcome to Jerusalem.
T.B. Joshua Arrives At The Jerusalem Municipality To Meet With The Deputy Mayor Of Jerusalem
I hear you are a friend of Israel, a friend of ZAKA.
It’s very important for us and for all the people around the world.
T.B. Joshua Arrives At The Jerusalem Municipality To Meet With The Deputy Mayor Of Jerusalem
The municipal authorities are housed in the offices of the mayor of Jerusalem, located in Jerusalem district,
around Safra square in the Daniel Garden.
It is here that Prophet T.B. Joshua, accompanied by Rabbi Yehuda arrives for a meeting
with the deputy mayor of Jerusalem.
Shalom.
He is in charge of building and building and building more.
I am in charge of young adult families...
He makes sure the people get the "right culture", growing up in the right way.
The magic of Jerusalem is the fact that it’s diverse.
It’s not just a city of one colour; it has many colours and we can cooperate together.
Jews and non-Jews, we live all together.
He says that his office is in a beautiful place.
We are going to go out and see all the beautiful nature.
When they come back to their offices, their heads will work better.
The deputy mayor and the councilman then take the man of God on a tour of the office,
overlooking the ancient city.
T.B. Joshua Surveys Jersualem With Deputy Mayor Yosef Daitsh And Councilman Hanan Rubin
This is what we call the "New City".
T.B. Joshua Surveys Jerusalem With Deputy Mayor Yosef Daitsh And Councilman Hanan Rubin
This is 4,000 years old. In the days of the Holy Temple, this is the place over there.
This is the old city of Jerusalem and as Yosef said, it is a combination.
This is an Arab part of the city; Christians and Arabs are over there.
Jewish people and these are orthodox over there.
Beautiful, isn't it?
After showing the Prophet the beautiful views of the historic city of Jerusalem, which is over 4,000 years old,
they take a photograph together to remember this day.
T.B. Joshua Meets With Deputy Mayor Of Jerusalem Yosef Daitsh And City Councilman Hanan Rubin
This is the symbol of Jerusalem - the ‘Lion of the Tribe of Judah’.
The strong one, being able to stand for many years; 4,000 years.
It’s a symbol of the Kingdom of the Jewish people, Judah.
This is a symbol of the Jewish people – the lion.
Deputy Mayor Of Jerusalem Presents T.B. Joshua With The Lion of the Tribe of Judah Pin
OK, nice.
In a gesture of appreciation, the deputy mayor fastens the Lion of the Tribe of Judah pin to the Prophet's shirt.
T.B. Joshua Presents The Emmanuel TV Team Book To The Deputy Mayor Of Jerusalem
Prophet, I have something here; I think this is an appropriate place to do this.
Prophet T.B. Joshua decided to become one of ZAKA’s leaders,
helping people no matter what religion they are – Jews, non-Jews, from Israel and all over the world.
The Chairman, Rabbi Yehuda Meshi Zahav, wants to give you a token of appreciation.
We give it only to special people who know that our role is to give to one another.
Rabbi would like to give this to you together with the Deputy Mayor of Jerusalem,
showing our appreciation for all that you have done and are going to do
towards helping other people all over the world.
You deserve much more but this is a small symbol from us.
Rabbi Yehuda Meshi Zahav Presents T.B. Joshua With The ZAKA Shield Of Humanity Award
In our Scriptures, it says, if you save one soul, it’s like you save the whole world.
It looks like you have saved a lot of souls.
This is the voice of Jesus. If you save one soul, you save the whole world.
Thank you.
Together with the deputy mayor of Jerusalem, Rabbi Yehuda presents T.B. Joshua with
the ZAKA Shield of Humanity Award, in recognition and deep appreciation of the Prophet's vision and mission
to reach out in love to a troubled world.
T.B. Joshua Meets With Deputy Mayor Of Jerusalem Yosef Daitsh And City Councilman Hanan Rubin
It was a privilege and honour for us to have you here.
Thank you.
We will continue coming.
This is our home.
T.B. Joshua Meets Deputy Mayor Of Jerusalem Yosef Daitsh And City Councilman Hanan Rubin
Everybody who helps Jerusalem gets back double and triple.
So, continue helping Jerusalem and you will have a lot of success.
T.B. Joshua Meets Deputy Mayor Of Jerusalem Yosef Daitsh And City Councilman Hanan Rubin
After the presentation of the award in the deputy mayor's office, they escort Prophet T.B. Joshua
into the Jerusalem municipality hall.
The Deputy Mayor of Jerusalem Yosef Daitsh Leads T.B. Joshua Into Jerusalem Municipality Hall
There are 21 members of the city council.
Up there you will see symbols of the 12 tribes of Israel.
It is said in the Bible that Jerusalem was the only place that was for everyone.
It represents unity, where people like Yosef, me and others can sit together in Jerusalem.
The Deputy Mayor of Jerusalem Yosef Daitsh Leads T.B. Joshua Into Jerusalem Municipality Hall
Explaining the importance of the Jerusalem municipality hall as a place of unity,
they show the Prophet around and ask the Prophet to bless the gathering.
Rabbi asks if you could give them a blessing for all the work they do.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
The Deputy Mayor of Jerusalem Yosef Daitsh Leads T.B. Joshua Into Jerusalem Municipality Hall
PROPHET T.B. JOSHUA VISITS THE CITY OF HEBRON
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits The Holy Land And Journeys To Hebron
During his visit to the Holy Land, Prophet T.B. Joshua travels south of Jerusalem to the cave of the patriarchs,
the tomb of Abraham, Isaac and Jacob in Hebron, ancient Judea.
As recorded in Genesis 23, "Afterward, Abraham buried his wife Sarah in the cave in the field of Machpelah
near Mamre (which is at Hebron) in the land of Canaan".
This is the visit of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Welcome.
Abraham buried his wife Sarah here.
Why did Abraham bury his wife Sarah here?
He bought this from Ephron.
Why did he buy this place?
Because he knew that Adam and Eve were buried over here as well.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits Cave Of The Patriarchs - The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
As recorded in Genesis 25, "Then Abraham breathed his last and died at a good old age,
an old man and full of years".
His sons, Isaac and Ishmael, buried him in the Cave of Machpelah near Mamre.
There Abraham was buried with his wife Sarah.
Above this big structure, there is a church from the time of the Crusaders which was built on top of this structure.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits Cave Of The Patriarchs - The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
This is the Seventh Step.
The Jews used to come to the Seventh Step, which is over here.
Today, thank God, since we liberated in 1967, we can enter the cave.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits Cave Of The Patriarchs - The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
When we speak about the actual graves, you have to understand they are three stories down.
Herod built this structure; then the Turks, the Ottomans came and built this structure.
And because it is a holy place, they built two mosques on top.
And still today, we have a church on the roof which was built in the time of the Crusaders.
Come, please.
The history of this Biblical site is recalled, as Prophet T.B. Joshua arrives at the entrance
to the Cave of the Patriarchs.
Let us follow his journey, as he visits the tombs of Abraham, Isaac and Jacob,
who requested in Genesis 49, "Bury me with my fathers in the cave that is in the field of Ephron".
"There they buried Abraham and Sarah his wife,
there they buried Isaac and Rebekah his wife,
and there I buried Leah." (Genesis 49:31)
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits Cave Of The Patriarchs - The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
As Prophet T.B. Joshua makes his way up the steps, not just to see the resting place of the heroes of faith
but to honour the God they served.
We cannot help but remember the voice of Jesus in Matthew 22, "Have you not read what God said to you,
‘I am the God of Abraham, the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob’?"
He is not the God of the dead but of the living.
Tomb of Abraham.
Tomb of Sarah.
At this precious site of the burial place of father Abraham and his wife Sarah, some of the heroes of faith,
Prophet T.B. Joshua prays.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits Cave Of The Patriarchs - The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
His heart deeply engaged with God,
Prophet T.B. Joshua spends a moment at the tomb of Abraham,
adorned with references to the Holy Scriptures.
Handwritten Hebrew Scriptures At The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits Cave Of The Patriarchs - The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
The Cave of the Patriarchs – four patriarchs and matriarchs were buried here 4,000 years ago.
You are touching the Bible here, the Old Testament.
Please, come.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits Cave Of The Patriarchs - The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
Continuing around the outside of the structure, Prophet T.B. Joshua makes his way to the wall that is believed
to surround the exact location of the resting place of Abraham and Sarah, Isaac and Rebecca, Jacob and Leah
- a sacred site, which has become a place of prayer.
Standing with Rabbi Yehuda Meshi Zahav, Prophet T.B. Joshua offers a prayer to the God of Abraham,
Isaac and Jacob, in Jesus' name.
He then continues through the spiritual monument.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits Cave Of The Patriarchs - The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
We are standing here; this rock where we stood is what is called the Seventh Step.
Because so many people, generations, over hundreds of years stood in this place,
like the Wailing Wall and prayed and cried and asked God for whatever,
today we believe that if someone comes and also sits here and has a problem in life,
and wants to ask God for something, anything -
for a medical problem, financial problem or fertility problem,
people come here to pray and God hears and accepts their prayers.
The tradition is that this is the entrance to Paradise.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits Cave Of The Patriarchs - The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
Hi.
How are you?
I'm great.
It is nice to see you here.
Thank you.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits Cave Of The Patriarchs - The Tomb Of Abraham, Isaac And Jacob In Hebron
Prophet, we are standing here near an olive tree orchard.
Somewhere over here was King David’s palace.
King David became king in Hebron.
He was king for 40 years – 7 years in Hebron and another 33 years in Jerusalem.
As 2 Samuel accounts, David asked, 'Where shall I go?' 'To Hebron', the Lord answered.
Then the men of Judah came to Hebron, and there they anointed David king over the tribe of Judah".
Welcome to one of the most ancient places in Israel, maybe in the world.
Please come.
Prophet T.B. Joshua continues past David's Hebron palace and the tombs of Abraham, Isaac and Jacob
to a hilltop near the Cave of Machpelach and enters a small ancient edifice, the tombs of Jesse,
father of King David, and Ruth, the great-grandmother of King David.
This is believed to be the tomb of Jesse, father of King David, and Ruth, the great-grandmother.
Hi.
How are you?
Thank you.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Inside The Tomb Of Jesse And Ruth In Hebron
This is a ram's horn.
We believe, on our special day once a year, that when we blow this, anyone who hears the sound should think
about all the bad they did around the year and make sure that next year, they're not going to do it again.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Inside The Tomb Of Jesse And Ruth In Hebron
Prophet T.B. Joshua On A Hilltop In Hebron - The Site Of The Tomb Of Jesse And Ruth
Continuing through the complex, Prophet T.B. Joshua arrives at yet another ancient structure.
Prophet, there are hundreds of structures like this in Hebron.
I want to show you something.
This is an old structure, probably dated about 1,000 years ago.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In Hebron Near The Site Of The Tomb Of Jesse And Ruth
Making their way out of the small entrance at the back of the structure, barely large enough to pass through,
they find themselves in an open grassy field in front of another edifice.
Passing through a tiny opening reveals an ancient room,
where Prophet T.B. Joshua immediately kneels down to pray.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Prays In An Ancient Synagogue In Hebron
Prayer is the shortest route between your heart and God.
God Almighty delights in hearing the prayers of His righteous children.
We pray not to pull God to our mind but to bring ourselves to His.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In Hebron Near The Site Of The Tomb Of Jesse And Ruth
Prophet T.B. Joshua At The Tomb Of Jesse And Ruth Near The Cave Of The Patriarchs In Hebron
Leaving the tombs of Jesse and Ruth, Prophet T.B. Joshua returns to the area believed to be the location
of the Hebron palace of King David.
As he surveys the grassy field, one can only imagine the view of the area in the time of David, a man whose
a man whose devotion and commitment to God and His Word
earned him divine recognition as a man after God's own heart,
a man who prayed in Psalm 130, "I wait for the Lord, my soul waits and in His Word I do hope.
My soul waits for the Lord, more than those who watch for the morning".
Somewhere over here, we believe was the castle of King David.
What I can tell you for sure is that King David, as a young shepherd, used to walk around here.
That was 4,000 years ago.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Visits The Traditional Location Of King David’s Palace In Hebron
Prophet T.B. Joshua In The Holy Land, Hebron
We are looking East.
In the Southeast was the Biblical city of Sodom.
Lot, the brother of Abraham, came from Sodom.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In The Holy Land, Hebron
God said He was going to annihilate Sodom because of the bad things happening there.
Abraham speaks to God and says that maybe there are 100 righteous in Sodom.
God says no and Abraham asks if maybe there are 50 righteous in Sodom.
50, 40, 30, 10 - not 1.
And then God annihilates Sodom.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In The Holy Land, Hebron
During the day, if we were here, we could look into Jordan.
We would see the Dead Sea; we are looking East.
What happens after Abraham, our father, speaks to God?
He says the first prayer to God in the world.
It is believed to be over here.
We are standing in the place where the first prayer to God was prayed to God.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In The Holy Land, Hebron
Let's go to the structure over here.
Entering a small structure on the hill, a Bible is opened and they begin to read.
“And the Lord appeared to him by the terebinth trees of Mamre” (Genesis 18:1).
Mamre is 1 kilometre South of here.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In The Holy Land, Hebron
“As he was sitting in the tent door in the heat of the day” (Genesis 18:1).
Abraham was sitting in the heat of the day and three angels came
and told Abraham that Sarah was going to have Isaac.
It happened 1 kilometre South of here.
This is where Abraham prayed the first prayer to God
and this is also the place where Abraham and Lot separated.
Lot went back to Sodom and Abraham went the other direction.
There is a tradition here and we are not sure which tradition it is, regarding these footprints.
We don’t know which tradition it is but it says these footprints are of Abraham when he prayed.
Do you see those two footprints?
It is a tradition. We think...
I brought an archeologist here about two months ago.
He told me that this is a Christian structure because it faces East, South East.
This is a Christian structure that was built 900 years ago.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In Hebron At The Footprints Of Abraham
These are believed to be the footprints of Abraham, our father.
Please come.
You can step here.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In Hebron At The Footprints Of Abraham
I want to remove my shoes.
OK.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In Hebron At The Footprints Of Abraham
James 2:23, "And the scripture was fulfilled which says, 'Abraham believed God,
and it was accounted to him for righteousness, and he was called the friend of God".
I want to pray.
In whatever form you pray, if our action is genuine, the Holy Spirit will affect it.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Prays In The Footprints Of Abraham In Hebron
Prophet T.B. Joshua In Hebron At The Footprints Of Abraham
We left Jerusalem, we drove South on route 60 - this is the "Kings Road".
We drove to Hebron.
Then we drove out of Hebron and we took a right turn down here and we are right here.
We'd looked East into Jordan as I told you, and we would see the Dead Sea if we were here during the day.
Of course, it is not enough that Abraham our father was here.
Who was also here?
This is where King David wrote The Psalms as he fled from King Saul.
There is a village here at a junction, called Ziph.
It says in the Bible, that when King David, before he was king, was fleeing from King Saul,
because King Saul wanted to kill him, he was hiding in the village of Ziph.
The Ziphim came and wanted to extradite him to King Saul but it didn't happen in the end
because he said a special prayer to God.
It happened 500 meters from here.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In Hebron At The Footprints Of Abraham
This is from the Rabbi, myself and Mati for you.
Thank you.
It will be a good memory from here.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In Hebron At The Footprints Of Abraham
Prophet T.B. Joshua In The Holy Land, Hebron
Prophet T.B. Joshua is shown an ancient well with a vast water reserve beneath the surface,
that could had served the people of Israel during its day.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Prays At Traditional Location Of The First Recorded Prayer In The World, Hebron
Concluding this spiritual journey overlooking the ancient grounds of Hebron, Prophet T.B. Joshua takes a moment
for reflection in a sacred place, where God Almighty communed with His holy people,
as we can read in the Bible today.
As it was, so it is; the Lord speaks to our hearts through His Word by His Spirit.
And when God speaks, the wise listen.
Prophet T.B. Joshua In The Holy Land, Hebron